Here you can see hierarchy view lets you select from
a list of devices with physical and virtual on the left,
each of which then contains each of the running activities
and applications running on that device. You simply select the activity
from the application that you want to profile. Then, hit
the Load View hierarchy button here, and you'll see a representation
of the selected activity's entire view hierarchy represented here in the
Tree View, from left to right. You can see that the
entire hierarchy is also shown here, in the overview and the layout
itself is shown in a wire frame here. Clicking on any view,
at any point within the hierarchy, will show you what is displayed,
showing us the number of views which are contained within the hierarchy
from this point onwards. You can also obtain the performance metrics to
find out how long it takes to measure, layout and draw each
element of the hierarchy. It's a powerful tool and you can find
out more about how to use it to optimize your layouts and
views in the videos and guides linked to from the
instructor notes below. For now, note that we can use
it to find surprisingly deeply nested layouts that need to
be flattened. For example, here we have a layout we
can describe using one of two techniques. One solution is
using two nested linear layouts. But a better solution would
be using a relative layout. The relative layout is one
level shallower. Another tip is to avoid using the frame layout
as the root for layout that will always be inserted
as a child into another one. In these circumstances, the merge
tag is a better alternative. This will be eliminated when the
layout is included into the parents hierarchy. To help you remember
all of these tips and tips, Android has a powerful static
analysis tool called Lint. As you can see here in the
lint window, in addition to the layout warnings we've already talked
about, it also checks from
everything from accessibility problems, missing translations,
and hard coded strings. You can find all the things lint checks
for at the developer tools page linked to in the instructor notes